Luis Souza

Mobile, Web and Application Developer & Designer

Advanced knowledge of Mobile, Web and Application development and programming languages.

Education and experience focused on both sides - tech & business - and plus, project management, leadership and design.

Education

2018-09 2020-04 Mobile Application Design & Development

Algonquin College - Ottawa | ON

Magna Cum Laude with Honours | Dean's List (2019/2020)

Cumulative GPA: 3.88/4.0

2004-01 2006-02 **Business Management**

Anhembi Morumbi University - Sao Paulo | BR

Cumulative GPA: 8.8/10.0

Certification

2020-03 Design Thinking Practitioner | IBM

Professional Experience

2021-04 Present

Full Stack Developer

PHD Solutions - Burlington | ON

- Developed WPF (Windows Presentation Foundation) application using .NET Framework and Web APIs for AWS (Amazon Web Services) environment.
- Published Web APIs in AWS API Gateway and Windows application in AWS S3 (Simple Storage Service) for the application user's access and versioning control for updates.
- Monitored Web APIs access and use with AWS CloudWatch.
- · Supported the application databases in AWS DynamoDB improving them whenever needed.
- Developed and support existing code and new features.
- Documented changes, new features and fixes to the Client's Release Notes.

2021-01 2021-03

Web Developer - Style Expert

Coach Association of Canada - Ottawa | ON

- Converted a whole web application developed in ASP.NET to be responsive for the web.
- Reviewed all the CSS styles applied for a system web application with 18K+ lines using SASS.
- Organized, normalized and grouped all the styles generating 75+ major groups.
- Reviewed and applied WCAG 2.0 AA to all possible conditions.

2020-04 Present

Software Developer

Fitted - Startup - Ottawa | ON

- Developed the iOS App features with Swift 5, using AR Kit 3 (Augmented Reality), Apple ID, Google and Facebook SDKs, with Apollo, GraphQL and PostgreSQL.
- · Supported the Web application developed in React with GraphQL and PostgreSQL.

- 敵 160 Hughson St South Hamilton, ON, L8N 3V2
 - **(**613) 618-4878
 - lhmscanada@gmail.com
 - appdevcanada.qithub.io

Programming Languages

Swift	••••
Kotlin	•••00
JavaScript	
HTML	
CSS	
Java	••000
C#	
C++	••000
React	
React Native (€ / ⊕)	•••00
Xamarin	•••00

Tools

Visual Studio

DBs (Oracle/SQL/Mongo)

XCode	
Docker	•••00
Android Studio	•••00
Visual Studio Code	
IntelliJ	••000
SASS	•••00
Git/Github/GitLab	•••00
Node.JS	••000
Adobe Illustrator/Photoshop	•••00
Adobe Xd/Figma/Sketch	
Cordova (€ / ⊕)	••000

•••0

Skills

Data Visualization	•••00
WCAG 2.x	•••00
Augmented Reality (ARKit)	•••00
REST APIs	••••
Google APIs	••••
Project Management	••••
Object-Oriented Prog.	•••00
User Interface (UI)	••••
User Experience (UX)	•••00
Design Thinking	••••
IoT (Internet of Things)	••••

Languages

••••
•••00
••••

Luis Souza

Mobile, Web and Application Developer & Designer

160 Hughson St South Hamilton, ON, L8N 3V2

**** (613) 618-4878

■ Ihmscanada@gmail.com

appdevcanada.github.io

2020-06 2020-08

Full-Stack Developer / Research Assistant

Algonquin College | Driven High Performance Lab - Startup - Ottawa | ON

- Designed the framework and Information Architecture from Backend to Frontend, with data analytics and development tools.
- Developed the MERN (Mongo/React/Express/Node) stack solution using NiFi data analytics, Matlab, MongoDB Atlas, React Frontend, Javascript API with libraries Ant Design data visualization, Plotly, Redux, Mailgun and Express, all in IBM Cloud with Docker.

2020-01

Team Lead / iOS Developer

2020-04

Algonquin College | Fitted - Startup - Ottawa | ON

- Planned, managed, arranged and followed up all the main tasks (±100), with a team of 14 resources and stakeholders.
- Built the Augmented Reality feature for the iOS App using Swift with ARKit 3.
- Deployed the project on time and scope with 20 most important requirements.

2019-09 2020-04

Program Assistant

Algonquin College - Ottawa | ON

• Supported around 40 to 60 students of the Programs Mobile App Design & Dev (MADD) and Internet App and Web Dev (IAWD), assisting them to accomplish 5+ assignments each and solving technical issues, bugs and environment-settings, for all the program languages as Javascript, React, React Native, Swift, Kotlin, Xamarin, Java, C++, C#, HTML, and CSS.

2019-05 2019-09

Software Developer / Research Assistant

Algonquin College | HTO - Ottawa | ON

- Developed an IoT (Internet of Things) solution with C++, controlling devices like temperature sensors, BLE (Bluetooth 5), Ethernet and Wi-Fi integration with Web Server and JSON file in a real-time application.
- Figured out a way and a combination of 4 components to bypass hardware/ software issues and deployed the solution working completely.

2018-11

Software Developer / Project Assistant

2019-08

Algonquin College | Makerspace - Ottawa | ON

- Created small apps in Google Sheets using G Suite APIs to manage the 3D printing pool and physical access to the lab, providing better feedback to the users related to taking back the printings.
- Established some Makerspace controls creating safe user guidelines, procedures and KPIs to manage staff and students' projects.

2012-06

Lead Web Developer

2015-12

SulAmerica Insurance Co. - Sao Paulo | BR

- Created one in-house web app, using G Suite APIs and third-party SDK, to coordinate 60+ corporate IT projects with dash-boards, allowing the project managers and internal clients to contribute and follow up on their projects and forecasts.
- · Designed the appearance, layout and flow of the Web site following the company's guidance and style.
- Developed the main components of the solution and implement coding standards to be followed by the team, with cross-browser compatibility in a graded browser support environment.
- Worked with the Database and Architecture teams to explain the solution, find and solve issues.
- Supported the presentation of the technical proposal for the board members.

2002-12 2007-02

Full-Stack Developer / Project Coordinator

2 | SulAmerica Insurance Co. - Sao Paulo | BR

- Coded one Health full-stack app in Visual Basic/MS-SQL using biometrics data to identify 1000+ clients a day.
- Oversaw Medical Web App Services using Java (J2EE, Struts, EJB, JSP and WebSphere), CICS/Cobol, Oracle and DB2 development in a day-by-day operational support team.
- Brought better results to the company and helped increase the annual revenue (intangible) due to better data controls, in a variety of environments, platforms, clients and a diverse support team with 10 resources (skills and experiences).

